Okay.
What...thank you guys for joining me now it's?
Late at six thirty.
It's kind of weird being like the dinnertime entertainment I'm here every day at six thirty and
ten thirty try the viel tip your server we'll talk about ...tear going to talk about maker
stuff with coyote I've got a massive array of demos if you came and
saw like the fervent preparation for all these things hopefully it all
lance there's an amazing quantity of wires and boards blinking things
and demos and I'm really excited to be able to share this stuff it's kind of
a combination of a couple of years of work from our team a lot of people here onsite back and rabin
have been helping kinda get a lot of this stuff ready so, without further ado let's march forward.
I'd like to start just by...contextual icing of this whole this whole hardware
thing I don't how many of you guys kind of grew up as hardware people we just.
Yeah, so, good chunk of the crowd and the rest I assume software people.
Ok, there's a bunch of people didn't raise hand so...
Farmingpainting something like that I was assuming kind of a mix between
hardware and software I...up as the software guy soI
like to contextualized where we are in this exciting hardware space back with my experiences
and software and what I found is there were a few interesting trends that drove people
to do all this cool software stuff that kind of exploded in
app stores and application...the first thing is development got really easy
used to be that to be a software developer maybe, you know, when I was a kid you
had to be this ninja that really understood the finer details of how
machines worked in you were able to code in see and assembly and it was just a high
bar and today it's very simple to write software modern tools are
awesome the second major trend that is really affected applications
...a ready market to go use those applications
and primarily driven by the mobile phone the mobile smart phones has
...fact that almost everybody particularly here
north america everybody's got one of these so you've got these sockets better ready to
sell into and people want to buy these applications because let's face it sometimes you're waiting for
bussing candy crashes way to kill some time the third one is low
friction distribution that not only is they're kind of a ready market but as
a software developer through app stores that market is completely and
very friction leslie available to me I can,
you know, pay of feed to a platform vendor usually
...exchange for that fear will pay I can get my software out anybody who wants?
And, finally there's this opportunity that I think is a little bit was
...and then we recognize that as an industry for enduring relationships used to be that when you
bought software it was kind of release over release activity to buy software license I
would you go in by piece of software and then, you know,
when v next came out I would have another conversation with the vendor maybe by that
...instead it's really changed up such that vendors want to build relationships with
our customers not just to sell version over version but you know,
in game purchases of content or to be able to do things like
hammering my microsoft band and this provides me sort
of ongoing engagement through some of the analytics...provides about my level
of physical activities those kinds of things that are provided continuous engagement
so the way I think about it I think things are just the new apps and the reason
why we get kind of pumped up about this is where replying the same trends in the hardware
space guess what hardware developments become really easy thanks to raspberry
...thanks...we know in particular tools like that ...modular it's like,
you know, as software developer I grew up doing modular development putting things in,
you know, first structuring them and functions and trying not to make too much spaghetti and then I
...classes and things like that harbors kind of the same way I can take a base
...shields on it I can attach lures to it and it's very modular and all these modules are
designed to work independently and be aggregated into one solution very easy to do in the
software tools to build those things are also very easy-to-use there's become a ready market
inaccessible market if I look at things like being able to go
andsponsor purchasing some particular piece of hardware that somebody's building like on
...starter and it's easy for me to get there and I ot is not a scary thing for people to
biif you look...moderation as one spaces an example people are afraid of going
...that stuff they're ready to go do it the ready to bring these things into their homes now
the challenge for all of us in the room I think is I think we've
won when every new device that somebody
acquires makes their world incrementally richer today?
And, I do this myself every new device
I acquire makes my life sometimes a little more complicated little more fun in totally
...don't get me wrong I totally cool with it but it gets a little more complicated
I think crossing the...for us means making it simpler for people
things like kick starters I mention make distribution super simple to get my product
out there to market I don't have to go do some deal with major retailers and people who have
...of customers I can get directly to those customers and
like software the sale of my hardware gives me
the opportunity create an enduring relationship with my customer through the data that my
device generates typically or through the way I want my device interoperate with other devices that might be
in the neighborhood so those are kind of the trends I thought I just go into a little bit about you know,
this raspberry...in particular and I have a few up here some of the things I'll be talking about I'll be
talking aboutgps...quite a bit but you'll hear these terms and I just kinda
wanted to give you the brief primus if you think about
...as a as a technology that I can use to drive hardware it's a
protocol that you might think of like tci express is higher-speed and there
are fewer of those pins available on a particular board usually than there are I squared
see pants which are lower speed more available I squared see
...a protocols actually a little bit more complicated but,
those are kinda how I will drive hardware in gps ios kind of like gi why it's like
ours to thirty-two serial port kind of stuff I can just do whatever I want to do over dpi
on a lot of the demos I'll show today I'll show using
...because it's kind of the simplest thing to do.
So, now let's drill into this raspberry pipe word I've got all these
pins that you see along the right side of the screen and,
if you look at the labels you'll see that there's a chunks that are our there's a
chunk that are sp ire gps io and you could tell by the color the
...and...and the gps audio is in orange and the
powers and yellow actually the three-point-three wel powers and yellow in the
...powers and read and,
just kind of going through this I can see okay that now I'm getting...I can kind of connect things to these...and
then I can drive these...and I can make some hardware this raspberry pi to board which I'm showing
so my demos has a number of other interesting things about it too I can
attaches display to it I can go from that display porter I can go from html
I can attach a camera adaptor to it supports a network card that I can connect to it's got...
usb ports and, it's got underneath...says display it's got a space for...so I can put in
...card and on that...card I can put an operating system that I want to choose to
So, that...very pi...the other things I hit on the session is often a little bit about our do we know
...this is are...you know, probably the most popular model...we know and you
could see some analogues, you know, pins for our pins for dpi opens for
...if I want to drive things I can...our I can connected to the
network sometimes people ask what's the difference between raspberry...and
...do we know why what...use one over the other and the short answer is that raspberry pie you can think of
as a small computer that has some io capability that's got all those pins that I
just showed you in that so works really well that way...really optimize
to work directly with the hardware so there's no operating system intermediate
...between the software which they call sketch the software you write that runs on that hardware
and,...and the hardware itself like you're talking directly to the hardware and art we are
typically has the ability to drive a little bit more our through the pin so you can often drive
...your hardware through...we know that you might be able to through raspberry pi...the other
...reply has a microprocessor instead of
a microcontroller so I can write apps and I can do algorithms and I can do lots of
cool interesting things using a computer that I might not be able to do using a microcontroller I'll
talk about a little bit how to mix these two worlds because we think we've hit upon some interesting kind of what we
call internally the big brain little brain I want a little brain to drive my hardware...big bring to drive my software
and algorithms.
So, let's start with a quick demo let me first introduce you to this piece of hardware let me ask
is I'm doing this how many of you have had the opportunity to go visit
...hands-on area with some of the raspberry
pie stuff gap that's awesome good chunk of people.
...make sure your...almost number four my first audio-visual
...let's see if I'm successful I am.
Except for the blurring this.
There we go so I'm looking at this at this board right here this is the more
that I'm using and I've got this little bred...attached pay no attention to the circus looking
blinking thing that's over here that is something that will play with later so this is a raspberry
pilot very much like the thing we just saw I've got a couple pins connected to this raspberry
pie as you can see right here driving
powering ground I've got a I've got an
...connected to this bread board and I've got a little resistor so that I don't blow up my
alley and what I want to do with this demo...blink this...the on
and off so I thought I just kind of walk you through the software that I would write to do that?
All right so farm to for to on av switches so I'm feeling really good about this.
...this is harder than it looks sometimes.
All right so just to
just kind of prefilter what I'm going to do here is I'm going to set up this by the way is just the universal
app it's just a windows app this isn't some special crazy like raspberry
...flavor windows...as a windows app I'm using the
dpx support that...part of the universal windows platform if I'm trying to
run this application on a system that doesn't have dpi...it
will just fail gracefully there's some air tracks in...that will enable to just kind of fail gracefully but this
app will run like it will load and run if I were to compile run this
up on my laptop on my phone so, just to be clear this is just a universal windows
at I just set up a little timer because I want be able to time when I'm
had the frequency of the flashing of my of my
And, the interesting code here I can walk through and order interesting code here
initialize is...just a few lines of code rtp audio...got dot get
...now what is gps...thing come from if I
were to if I were to look at the tool tip over this windows dot devices that
gps ios so this is one of our namespaces this is a windows name space so,
this is built right into the platform and I'm able to use that I'm able to get there's only one
...who get defaults going to work there's a couple error
checks here and then I can open the pin make sure that the
pin is initialize properly and then I can write a value to that...I can write to that
pin to get it turn the...dionne I'm using a little little identifier here
...depend which is simply the number of the gps open that I'm connected
to...scroll down and show you what that identifiers it's just five
so on that map that I showed you that showed all the pins if you were to...that map you would
find dpi open five which is actually something like pin number twenty-eight on the
board it gets interesting to map sort of physical to virtual pins.
Couple more things every time the timer...I flip the...on or off so.
Flipping...just the exercise of writing
...on or off to that pin and changing the user interface
to switch on off so I've actually written a little user interface here
apparently doesn't like the interface that I've written herelong-term bring that up again.
It'll run right you think.
...give it a whirl...just it ok so let me do this let me let
me start running this on the remote machine by the way notice my although I'm on
a surface three as my dev machine but my debug...sets
remote machine my remote machine is this raspberry pie up here on the on the table that you
were just looking at and if I were to go to debug
...properties.
And, I can show you the ip address this is just the ip address up here of the
sport I'm able to debug too it just like I would debug
...windows system so there's nothing really special I have to do to be able to do that
if you're using our image forI guess there's no other image to use for the raspberry
pi so when you use our windows image for the raspberry pi
it's the remote...already set up for you to go ahead and use so you don't have to do any kind of configuration for
...debugging is already they're already ready let me go ahead and run this.
So, you should see the output cooking and meanwhile me see if I can switch over inputs.
There you go so that's the
way you're seeing now up on the screen is the output of the html
...my raspberry...so that is a universal windows application running
the blinking is coinciding with the blinking that I have here on my on my
screen which I can switch over and show you sorry I don't have like cool side-by-side or picture and picture
anything like that so you have to just kind of imagine what that might look like if you closure
...really tightly...them side-by-side there you go
...blanket that's kind of the canonical hello world of the hardware world.
Now another interesting thing I find about hardware one of the other reason
...steve theory of how the world works this isn't like science or anything or maybe it
is I don't know depending on if I'm science but this is just my theory and how the world works we use a
lot of touch-screen especially in our line of work like we're always, you know, touching our computers touching
our phones that's just kind of how we do things those of you that have kids that are maybe less
than eighteen-years-old will find that the first thing they do when they go up to a screen is?
Touches what did we do we like it was like...yell at you like I'm after window
...touch the screen but people of have
learn to manipulate physically which is interesting but what I think that touch-screen
...they're just a...mirage of the real-world they're not
really the real-world in fact I think humans actually prefer
tactile experiences they prefer to touch actual things not two-dimensional
representations of three-dimensional things and it's my belief that this is also one of the
drivers of what's happening in the maker space today and in the
hardware space today is giving
humans the opportunity to physically manipulate their world never mind that
those physical controls are just connected the bits and bytes just like if they were being painted on a two-dimensional
screen it's the fact that we can engage with these and visceral physical way makes it more
...pleasing for us as human beings and just some examples of some of these kinds
of switching experiences that we like to touch so what
we've we want to offer is a couple things one is this windows ten
addition io t core that was released yesterday and,
combined with visual studio and I've showed you both of those so far ready
today to be able to bring that into your world
...making stuff and I hope the way you receive this isn't that we're
here to say use our stuff instead of some other stuff I think what I'd what I'd
like you to walk away with is used, you know, tryout our stuff to try
out the tryout windows and tryout visual studio as well kind of attitude
your arsenal of tools that you might use to go make things I think...still
an absolute role to play for other operating systems in the space for other tools in the space for other hardware in
the space it's an enormous space and I
...we found some opportunities that I hope you'll agree by the time we get the into this presentation to
do cool stuff with the platform what it's additive it's not instead of?
So, many of you have seen these robots.
I've got one of these robots right here and
I can even I can even show you these robots on the overhead.
And, then I've got
to move on my blinking lights and everything let me see if I can get this guy over the
robots a bit of a challenge because it's I've managed to tether written several different ways
so I'm almost certain to break stuff as I go throughout the course
this presentation.
So, there...one I've got one of these robots here.
And, see if a...field.
There we go for wide-field you kinda see it so,
what the robot is it's a few laser cut
wouldn't parts and I've got a raspy...sitting on top that raspberry pi has and
...card loaded into the front of it as the card has windows ten
...core I'm connected to the pins on the top of my raspberry...
to drive a couple motors that can drive the wheels forward or backwards and,
then I've got kind of some screws and some connectors little ball bearing thing there so
it kind of runs flat and smooth I've got a little sensor here so that if
a bumps into something on the side it can stop it knows
it's bumped into something so that's essentially what you see here cute little robot
...I've got one that's now up here all plugged in
...ready to ready to do something so what I'm going to do is I'm going
to switch back toswitch back to visual studio
...project that we're working on to be able to manipulate this robot?
I'll tell ya no matter how the how the demos go the fact that I mastering av switching
...walk away feeling like a winner honestly?
All right so assuming I have the correct ip address in here and how do I know if
I've got the ip address we do have a tool that we've made available as a part of the package
...download that's called the windows it core watcher so this tool it'll
install along with the other tools what does it looks for other or look for windows
it core devices on the network
so happens that I'm sharing the network with a couple devices couple devices
up here once the robot when was the blinking device I've already change the default
passwords so anybody that thought about getting cute wanting to get
...make them do something different you're going to have to have my password first?
But, it tells me what the mac addresses what the ip addresses and I can do interesting things like
I can go to this text robot one which should be the
guided sitting up right here in front of me and I can also open a web browser interface
that device and we've given you a just for this release for kind of debugging and,
purposes of getting familiar with the platform being able to do some things that are difficult to
do otherwise because we're not quite complete yet you can do some configuration on the device what app is
it running can I loader unload apps from the device, you know,
tell me something about what the network situation is on this thing so
just a handy tool that you can use once you've got one of these windows t windows
multi-core devices up and running so here I am imap to robot app let me
we look around here the robot so a couple interesting
couple interesting things about the robot one is that again it's a universal app is a
headed universal lap so there's actually some screen output which is why I have the
html connected on this particular robot
and I'm using gp io to simply drive the wheels one direction or the other and,
I won't go through everything but just to show you some of the code that is used to
initialize the gps opens and some of the code that is used
to actually write a value...begin the motor to spinning so what I want to do now is I just want to
deploy this application...set to deploy the...remote machine
...arm all of that's good let's see if this works will be lovely?
That's never good sign sometimes it's not a disconcerting simon's never good
sign in what that's doing this I'm going to look and make sure I've got my ip address right.
All right that's as I may not have the right ip address going on so let's come back to
...core watcher that's why this thing is handy.
Copy the ip address.
Come back to visual studio.
Looks like it changed through wow that's disconcerting it changed since
right before the session when I set it up I don't know why that is maybe that's a bug someone in the room might
...file bug on that.
Okay, now it says starting deployment starting and
well that's starting to switch over now to the output of the robots html port.
And, there we go let's just kind of a little default app screen that the
it core produces.
A iq let's talk after his hard to hear the question up here so here's,
here's the here's the default screen for the application.
If it's working correctly I should be able to kind of use this guy to
drive which is good...see if I can show you back on the back on the elmo.
And, I'm running over a dot net micro framework board right now I don't mean anything by that it's
just happens to be where positioned ok so now it's around so what's cool
...I'm using an xbox controller to drive this thing if I
had a touch-screen the or mouse those buttons that you saw...the...I could use
those to manipulate the application as well but I did not plug-in a mouse and,
that's not a touch-screen turns out but,
I can use just regular xbox controller to drive this because we've
this-is just a regular shows up as a regular windows hid joystick that I can use
...manipulate I didn't really have to writing
...special coder...to handle the xbox controller just plugged in and,
... kind of defined what forward and back and side-to-side means so,
that's pretty neat let-me let me do this I'm going to just...the
bagger so I detach the...which means I've got the application hopefully still running on this
device because I want to get at in just a minute so,
with that application still running here's what I'd like to do I'm just going to change the target
of this application from armed x eighty-six and I'm going to say I want to
debug on the local machine instead of on a remote machine now steve you're crazy you
might say that was a application that was meant for robot not for laptop to run on
...your mistaken I would say I'm actually going to run it on my machine and let me
...you weren't looking where you you're,
you're looking at the other so here we go let me show registered I just changed.
Target ...x eighty-six and debugged locally so
with that I'm just going to hit the green arrow and if everything goes well.
There is so now I've got the same exact application that you saw...the output of the raspberry
pi robot here on my screen and if
this works appropriately what I should be able to do is...this other
xbox controller that's actually connected to my laptop so these robots what they do and
...when they start-up is a or the app starts up is it looks
for another application to connect back to so it found this instance of this
application running on my pc connect back to it and now I can if I switch
ci messed up switching one-time so now I don't feel like such a winner anymore,
you know, maybe I'll get my...back...if I switch back to?
Switch back...now you can see I can drive this thing so it was pretty interesting running the
exact same copy of the application whether I'm running on this device
whether running on a laptop and I just kind of change the control
...instead of driving the motors directly
my ipc center command over the network to the robot to go ahead and spin the motors.
All right we kind of looked at the robot.
...a little bit now about ...thing so,
typically when we build a thing where, you know, I talked about our do we know we can start with an art we know what the
really inexpensive to be able to build the thing that drives that drives hardware start with maybe
a thirty dollars we'll but if I want to do like I want to accelerometer ought to be able to tell, you know,
when I move and about...three-dimensional space so that's about another thirty bucks and then pardon
...if I want to do speech recognition...that's,
you know, it's kinda hard so speech recognition is about fifty bucks you add that then
you can one of the properties of shields are often made to be stable and you can stack
these things one on top of the other to be able to do things because they said on...that can
share that can share io channels and then what if I want some kind of touch-screen
display with nappy need if I could like tell where I was in space and time and I can
recognize speech and I can touch that's another city as you see like one as you start to
actually stack up in physical space and then you also
start to stack up in economic space it adds up as you add all of
the shields and then there's a whole bunch of things that you might want to do with one of these devices right you might
want to camera might want to...to something via bluetooth you might want
to do sd storage to be able to put stuff on it you might want to connect...network the cellular
wi-fiyou might need speech detection you might want to have vibration they're all these things that you
could imagine that small devices tend to do and their shields by the way that
you all of these things that you could buy you could stack them and, you know, you could have a really cool
look in device I'm just by stack and all this stuff but sometimes it can become unwieldy
inexpensive so one of the projects we've been working on...project we internally call project
margarita which is the universal windows platform bridge to the art we know platform this
is part of our announcement yesterday with our...we know and it's consistent with the
other universal windows application bridges that we've made for other platforms it's the
idea of saying hey wherever you are there's an easy way...to come in and also
in additive way leverage the capabilities of windows rather than in instead of way?
And, one of the ways that we thought about doing this is to say,
you know, we're pretty good at building these phones
that really high-volume we make a lot of the sm phones in the us anyway
you can buy I think this is technically a linear six twenty but you can find five twenty
five thirty six twenty six thirty for about fifty dollars usually with no contract really inexpensive
and if you think about all the cool thing you get inside of a phone if you think about it not
as a phone but as a maker device wow all those things on that list I get
an accelerometer I get a gps I get a big touch-screen get cellular
I get wi-fi I get bluetooth the list kind of goes on and on of all the cool things that
I could get if I could find the right ways to connect from like this to a device like...we know.
So,...start with when I when I
develop applications for my phone it's cool but, you know,
my phone is really bad at my phone is really bad
and driving hardware like I could you tapered we know to the back of my phone or, you know,
push buttons on it or something like that might be one way to do it it's, you know,
it's...unwieldy but that's one way I could do it one of the things that we announced here
build is this remote art we know wiring or remote...remote or do we know
a allows me to do something like from my phone I can build that app that kind of
...take a picture with my phone camera and then I can scale it
...it and do all the things that are storage and computationally intensive and hardware
intensive and then I can maybe send that over to the art we know to drive
some kind of some kind of experience and this idea of remote art
winter was pretty cool wanted to show you a couple of demos actually
of this thing so let me start let me start here?
So, now bring this guy on board so
this thing that kind of looks like frankenstein monster.
And, in addition to turning on...creator one of the other things that
it does is it's just a bunch of wires that are plugged into all
the various pins of an art we know so that I can drive that are do
we know remotely I just want to do this for demo purposes so what I've got here my setup
is I've got...know on top of the art we know is a whether shield that knows how to read
temperature and barometric pressure humidity and that sort of thing and then I've got from all
the from of io pins I've got a bunch of things that are driving a leads bunch of wires that are...
leads I've got a little potentially armor here that I can turn I've got a button that I compress and
then I've got a little little bluetooth shield here
that I'm using to be able to connect from this device to the world via bluetooth.
So, let's take a look at a couple things here.
Someone open up another visual studio project in this
...screen...I was still doing so good and then I completely fell off the wagon.
Okay, that's visual studio I side with here so,
this is visual studio and what I'm going to do is I'm going to this is an app that
is intended to run not on the start we...but it's intended to run on my phone and using remote art
window over bluetooth I can use my phone
to accessing control the capabilities of the...device so just a couple things from a code
standpoint I wanted to show you guys just to kinda get a feel for how this thing works one is in the
setup so you can see in the setup code I am a establishing a bluetooth
serial connection I am doing this new uw pfour
...thing creating a for...object which you can see is one of the namespaces
that we provide and same thing for this remote device in fact if
I look into if I look into this remote device?
...go to definition you can see that it's...metadata and what this remote devices is
it's kind of a it's kind of an api that is part of
the universal windows platform that's a representation of the things I can do via
and art window api so I can I can read I can...I can get the eyes...see
bus access I can do all of these things that I would be able to do but I've got a nice universal windows
platform api set that I can use to do that now I'm kind of passing this from
thing what for...is it's a standard it's a standard protocol for driving micro
...so I'm just going to use that standard protocol for microcontroller to
drive this particular...do we know to be able to do interesting things with it couple
other things I would just point out one is and let me show you what this application looks like
assuming I don't get the example...on this one and getting sam layers
and this one so I'll show you on the phone let me go ahead and deploying run this guy?
Ok, so, I'm...it now it's my phone.
So, now what you see on the screen is the phone that I'm using right here my
...just a picture of the screen what I'm going to do now is I'm going
to connect to the bluetooth device that's sitting
right here and that is happens to be this one I believe.
So, this is the why that wasn't I wasn't able to show you in visual studio but what this is just
it looks like the rails on the art we know it's just a representation of the different pins on the
or do we know so when I...I push buttons on my device here
and you can see I'm pushing a bunch of different buttons what's actually happening is?
On the device...lighting up the leads.
So, I'm driving this
...do we know from my phone and I haven't gotten to what's actually running on
...we'll get to that one second but, I can do other things like I can hit the
humidity button on my device which I'll show you in just one moment and it will read-out the
value from the whether...so when I hit humidity you can see that
says there's thirty two percent humidity which are that drive here didn't feel that drives me
...here I can't I should be able to for example,
play with the potentially ahmed earn you can see the number spin as I play with
...that's really cool so the question is what am I doing on the...we know
...kind of be able to get at it from my windows device like that it turns out that
the usa would please like stopped bugging it turns out that let me ...head over to the
...do we know id.
And, the...do we know id.
Contains a number of examples that are kind of come with our do
we know out-of-the-box including an example called standard for model.
So, there is so this is just
...stock standard for mod example that comes from...we know with their
...with their download this was the sketch that we loaded into the art
...device so literally I was able from a windows application using uw
p to drive all the pins and capabilities of this hard...device and I never even had to write
...or learn align of our do we know code I was able to deploy the standard for...
a sketch get that running and then once that's running on the...we...kind of the world
...might...or from a windows application it's really cool now this is a pretty simple example
in a somewhat contrived example to be able to show you all the things that light up
...more complex things that we could do as well and that's another thing I'd like to show.
So, let me.
...open up another example in dam...this is
...dan taking off the during the big reveal.
Ok,
so, this is when you like let the team go loose and you're like okay
...we want to do this with this remote...we know things that we can really
drives some hardware from a windows device other than having some really interesting
blinking leads what can we do and the answer courses a lot more leads
so what you see is a massive screen full of...
And, I'm almost certain we're not violating any local fire codes
or unique or ...
w electrical rules totally safe it's on its own circuit but what we have here
...we want to be able to rendering image that we can take from this phone
...to capture and image on this phone using the camera and then I want to be able
render that image over there to...to the leads using mired we know to
drive the leads and using my phone to handle all the processing load
...capturing the image and kind of raster rising the image to this smaller
think it's I don't remember how many pixels forty-eight by forty or forty by forty I don't even remember
...by forty and, if that would work that I think that would be pretty cool so,
let me let me start by trying the application out?
So, by the way it's worth noting that are although word windows are
...driving hardware they're fairly small
in modest compute devices in fact the array that you would
use for this set of pixels does not fit into the ram of the or do we know data
can...remind around that like wow like there's no frame buffer because?
You know, the frame is bigger than the buffer so how do you do that what we do is we do
all of that here locally on the.
On the windows phone and I'm seeing a deployment or let me make sure my...unlocked here.
...seeing all of that doing all of that processing on the windows phone and
then sending it sending the information sort-of bit-by-bit via blobs binary
blobs until a paints the entire screen.
And, it's registering.
Ok, so, now what you see is that is that application now in
this case we have made a look we have done a little bit of work to the standard for
...application that's running on this particular art reno shield so,
we've made some editing we did write a little bit of our do we know code to get
this from working let me try this let me see if I could me see if I could take a cellphone here.
Okay, here we go others a light behind me
it's going to be really hard to do but we'll see if we can capture my face there
we go...I'm looking down that is not my best picture that I've ever taken.
...going to tell to drive the screen.
So, how many...went to the session I did on t last year?
Yeah, I did this thing where I had this traffic light and I left it on so that like the guy in
the front-row got sunburned.
That was fun when that happened wasn't.
So, let's try this specific take picture you guys...how this ends up.
...taken a picture...are going to render that.
And, see.
Just the top of screens taken so yeah,
it's I think...the pixel on the.
So, anyway, great example of kind ofand, let me let me do this is...trick for.
Not some burning people see if this kind of works.
Is to take a picture of a black screen and then painted there we go there
are some trial-and-error involved in figuring out that solution believe me?
That's...kinda gives you an idea of...the kind of things that you would do if you can take this
remote wiring to its logical conclusion really using the our verge we know to drive hardware which is what
it's best that but recognizing the fact that it's not good having a lot of ram are being able
to image processing offloading network in this case my phone.
Now if I were to I'm just going to stop the debug session here
the code here is just to show you a couple pieces of code that are that I think
...interesting one is just kind of the same set of code to set up yes,
it's over bluetooth yes I'm using for model once again so similar pattern to what you
saw with my a small example here of the blinking leads and the potential
...and that sort of thing...this thing does...work is done by this
draught image function which is what takes the camera image
the kind of knows how to raster...based on the kind of ...of image that you want to
...to the screen and once it's done that it kind of...the shift
bites function over and over again for every blob of data and just kind of passes it
over the bluetooth channel intellect lights up every
...so pretty cool.
Let's see what else we have here.
So, what we showed was this idea that hey without really learning how to be
...art we know programmer I can use a windows phone combined with an art we
know to drive hardware what we'd also like to talk about is
this idea of windows virtual shield for art we know kind of the converse I can
...learning really how to be a windows developer I can from my
...we know code leverage all the capabilities from my phone just as if my phone
...a set of shields provide stacked on top of mired we know except in this case I want
to do it over bluetooth so that means things like the screen or things like speech
recognition they could just show up in mired
...world like a natural thing that like the same way that I would show up the with this weather
...that I would just put on top of the hardware?
So, let's take a look at what that might look like.
I'm going to go into...we know code now.
So, here's my here's mired we know code which you're going to see in just
one-minute there is so there's mired winner code using...we know id
...so looking at the art we know code if you're not familiar with art we know
...sketch language is a see like language
others pound includes there's curly braces there's function calls it's got
a kind of stuff the things I want to point out to you are the includes here
these are includes that are about the virtual shield so I want to be able to get
at the virtual shield support I want to get the screen which is graphics dot h I
want to get the accelerometer for my phone I want to be able to get
it speech recognition from iphone and I wanna-be able to get the web I want use my phone is
a conduit to the worldwide web via bluetooth or sorry
...cellular or via wi-fi however the phone might happen to be connected and,
just to show you a little bit of the...we know sketch code what the setup function does usually
...to functions at least set-up and loop what the setup function does is it sets up all
these shields it sets them up in such a way that they the action
becomes call backs so inside of our run function
it just includes a call to like execute on all the call backs when it's appropriate to do so,
I set up call backs and thenso,
I have call backs for things like hey when I get an event for
the for the screen this tells me or this is actually the
set-up event this tells me okay I want to draw some buttons on the screen and I'm
going to look up colors on wikipedia...what does that mean what them and you see the...got docket
so what this means is one of the things we wanted to do with this demo is we wanted
to use the web to go find all the colors that are in the creole
a color catalog so now creole has colors like tangerine
and burnt cnn all these kind of weird things we thought that would be a fun set of colors to go
...so there's actually a wikipedia page of course where you can go and look at all those
colors we grab that and then we're going to use those colors as part of
the speech recognition so that we can get the appropriate color drawn on...doing and,
we're just going to draw...a point on the or do we know so the web event all this thing does is
once it gets that response back from the wikipedia page parses it says great I've got that
information that's awesome and then we've got this other thing here that?
Draws to the screen based on the speech
...figures out here's the color you wanted I get the xy coordinates I draw a
on the screen that pixel which is a very big dp pixel that you want to see so,
let's see if we get this thing running what is really,
really neat about this particular demo?
Is I literally do not have to learn how to be a windows developer all I have to be
able to do is run windows application so we've written this application
herewhich is the virtual shield application it's not yet available in the store but
...made the source code available in fact I think the source code for absolutely everything I'm
showing you today with the exception maybe one demo is already on get hub you can get it everything you
could try that yourself...around with the including this application eventually
will be in the store so you don't even have to know-how to go get to you don't even have to
know-how to get to get have you just have to not go to the store some of...run this application?
So, all the code I've written sits over there on the...we know it's looking up the colors
...wikipedia...found them...hundred-twenty colors I only have the sixty-four color package of
...as I didn't really realize there was a one twenty...maybe they change over the years like
baskin-robbins only thirty one-at-a-time but the entire
...a flavors is actually fairly,
fairly big all right so I've got this I've got this guy go...so let me let me
...go let's see what happens
...redrawing all right so what should happen I can't see the screen so I'm just
...relying on...to tell me that things are...using the accelerometer so as I
...the phone it should be drawing the pixel in different places.
So, that's pretty that's pretty good if that's in fact happening nobody's brewing so
what's probably happening I feel pretty good about that...I'm going to
nominate hit on the phone and hit this color button and ask...to paint a different color.
...try one more tangerine.
Doesn't understand my accent?
Yeah, that seems to work ok what about.
So, you can see the upwards fun.
One of the things we thought a lot in working on windows coyote
...this idea of connectivity you know, if you attended a session I did was
sam george yesterday we talked a lot about connectivity...
devices and to me connectivity is what really represents the difference between imbedded
and io t imbedded devices... small computers imbedded in things that,
you know, exhibits independent behavior based on having onboard computer it becomes io
t when these devices can connect to the other devices around them and
...ambient environment and also connect to the cloud so we focused on that
and a couple different ways one is you'll find as we demonstrated yesterday ready connection up to
ashes...t infrastructure so
you're building out devices like this you have the ability to leverage the data that they
...gain interest interesting insights from the data that generates be able to
view data in real-time be able to find alerts and anomalous behavior and real-time
but then also gavin geared gave a session earlier this week about all join and,
all join as an investment that we've made in windows...available...all windows ten additions including
ip core as a local old sort...proximate network technology
for devices to talk to one another it's my point of view that devices, you know,
they want to be free that they want to talk to other devices they want to
talk to the cloud and, we only win this is one of those things where we only win-win
...we can light up that world...when I...device my world gets richer if you think about
it that world only happens when devices can talk to one another otherwise I'm thinking about okay
how do I only acquire devices that are in the particular walled garden ecosystem that I
maybe participating in...we just devices should just
know-how to talk to each other that should be the default behavior for devices.
Speaking of which I'd like to talk a little bit
about smaller devices and also talk about how they connect the altering to the world.
Dot net micro framework is a technology that we've worked on for several years
and it represents a smaller classes devices so those devices that we talked about our do we
...running on micro running microcontroller class silicon that is where dot net
micro framework works best these days typically that's represented by arm cortex
...three-m for classed silicon here
to new boards from one of our partners secret...they've got a great product called
net we know and it allows me to use micro framework gives me the ability from within csharp
in a dot net environment to write code that actually runs on these little tiny platforms
in many ways...many...very often that code that I write for these little
...alsoupward compatible to larger versions of dot net so
netting between...three wi-fi has onboard wi-fi between
three ethernet onboard ethernet and a couple of other partners we've worked with gh
...another big maker of dot net micro framework devices on the left you see
...gh...as spider kit which is taking the idea of
micro framework and then adding to it modular hardware so that I can plug on cameras
...and lots of different sensors and then what you see on the right
there is a prototype of a hat for raspberry
...to that allows me to kind of enjoy that modular hardware ecosystem that gh
gis been famous for
...to do that on top of raspberry pi to on windows ten not just on dot net micro
frameworks that's pretty cool I did want to show you one demo for dot net micro framework let me start by
showing you this board which is which is a monster for micro framework
board?
Within the big...the new small.
So, we've got this four that's like.
Size of my hand.
All of your door locks will be this big in the future believe me here to
value know what this is actually a development board for
micro framework so typically if you if you kind of work in hardware space what you'll find is
vendors and this one comes from arm vendors will give you these development boards that
...the so see that you want to target but then it's got all the ios and all the connectors and all
the support for everything that you might want to do with it and this is one of these ads heart it's a cortex
m for arm architecture and what I wanted to show is just
a little windows application here combined with my television so what
we've done is all join has a small form factor that's
designed for the smallest device like micro framework devices and using that
small form factor I'm able to create all join compatible
devices and put them are create these tiny things and put them in all joined
...tiny devices are...compatible so that I can have door locks
...can have lightbulb...can have the smallest things that speak all join not just bigger devices
like this windows machine here so I'm going to switch to my laptop?
So, what should come up here is a is a dot net micro framework project so you can see this dot
net micro framework project what this does very briefly is just sets up
sets up this device as a member of the ambient networks all
join bus because it is running the sm version of all join it looks
for a router that can connect to that it can allow it to connect other devices
...the outside world it so happens that router functionality is built
into windows devices including windows phone that I'm running here
so what will actually do...will communicating communicate from this dot
micro framework device to this windows device they can discover each other they can
they can shake hands they can get to know each other and then once it establishes that connection
between my phone and the sm micro framework device it can use my phone to
rout communication to other devices on my network including this television here which
this lg television also and this is a commercial that you can
...probably by across the street a target this particular
...speaks all join the commercial device that you can buy today that speaks altering so,
just to show you a couple pieces of code here there's just kind of big while true loop that this thing sits
in while it's running and it kinda
does some housekeeping first it make sure that gets an ip address setup it starts up
the all join service and make sure that the all join service get setup once the all join services
setup it looks for a router connects itself to that router?
And, then it kind of sits in a message pump loop handling messages and
...couple of interesting messages for this demo one is the phone is allowed to
...and the others the phone earth phone or any device...all join
...to read or write the value of the temperature and I've hard
coded the temperature for purposes of this demo at seventy so,
what I'm going to do is I'm going to run different different phone here looks the same but it's
actually different from?
And, let's come out here.
All right so I've got this application it's connected which means these two devices of already
...connected to one another what I can do is I can
read the temperature from this micro framework device and again using all join?
Okay, that's got it at seventy degrees and the other thing that I can do is I can
set the temperature and when I degrees fahrenheit current
temperature degrees fahrenheit?
...like a mix those kind of cool what we'll do is when I said it will send
...all join broadcast to say someone set my temperature if all goes well
the all join broadcast should be picked up by this television here in front so
that's going to click the send tv which was set in sentence broadcast?
...stage.
For sorry...stage.
That should be ok let me just try and make sure this
...run the application one-time let's see.
I'm sure it's going to be...totally going to work moi.
This kind of a finality in the way she says that isn't there.
I'm...to go with what core...tells me.
All right and a couple cost action I have for-you one is if you
haven't already please visit windows on devices dot com again,
be able to explore source code figure out how to set
...windows on your on your raspberry pi to in
aboard max devices here at the conference you can do the quick start challenge you can do the
...workshop so lots of things that you can do to kinda get engage and start
working on stuff now I do have one last thing as we're up against time.
...all you guys one of these cool robot kids ...
Thank you thank you for coming this the kid has a...it's got...card pre image with
...the robot kit components it's got sensors wires...
I wasn't going to do it because the micro framework thing failed I thought I showed you guys.
So, thank you for coming to build.
Enjoy the resolution.